DC Down is a action, thriller, tv movie film directed by Geoff Meed.
After an earthquake rocks D.C., the Army Corp races against the clock to rescue the President
trapped under the rubble while a sinister plot aims to capitalize on the disaster.
Lance Cushing, played by Jack Pearson.
President Powell, played by Sean Young.
Katherine Greene, played by Kayla Fields.
General Harris, played by Terry Woodberry.
Speaker Terry Wilder, played by Eric Roberts.
Beck, played by Geoff Meed.
The DC Universe (DCU) is an American media franchise and shared
universe based on characters from DC Comics publications.
It was created by James Gunn and Peter Safran,
co-chairmen and co-CEOs of DC Studios.
The DCU is a soft reboot of a previous franchise, the DC Extended Universe (DCEU),
retaining select cast members and narrative elements but disregarding others.
In contrast to the previous state of DC Comics adaptations, the DCU features a unified continuity
and story across live-action films and television, animation, and video games.
Concurrent DC adaptations that do not fit this
continuity are labeled "DC Elseworlds".
After Discovery, Inc.
and WarnerMedia merged to become Warner Bros.
Discovery (WBD), CEO David Zaslav revealed a plan to revitalize the
DC brand following the poor reception of the DCEU.
Gunn and Safran were hired to lead the newly formed DC Studios in November 2022 after working on several DCEU
projects, including the film The Suicide Squad (2021) and its spin-off series Peacemaker (2022–2025).
The pair spent several months with a group of writers developing the overarching story for a
new DC continuity that features a mix of popular and obscure DC characters.
Some DCEU projects in development were abandoned in favor of new takes, while
others—including Peacemaker—continued within the new franchise.
Certain DCEU actors reprise their roles in the DCU, with others recast.
Gunn and Safran wanted to focus on storytelling needs rather than forcing
creators to complete their projects to meet specific release dates.
The story of the DCU is divided into chapters.
The first chapter, "Gods and Monsters", begins with the first season of
the animated series Creature Commandos, released in 2024.
Gunn and Safran consider the chapter's first film, Superman
(2025), to be the true beginning of the DCU.
The tone is intense.